Guide to Carleen Hutchins papers M1734
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Carleen Hutchins papers
1900-2010
M1734
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
40.58 Linear feet (83 manuscript boxes; 2 flat boxes; 3 map folders, and 1 oversize item)
The papers relate primarily to musical acoustics, musical instrument construction, and her invention of the violin octet including research notes and papers; research notebooks; manuscript and published articles; lectures and lecture notes; charts, graphs, and drawings relating to musical instruments and acoustics; correspondence; photographs and slides; posters; and sound recordings on tape and cassette comprising 33 boxes.
Hutchins, Carleen Maley
Acquisition Information
The Carleen Hutchins Papers were a gift of Joseph McNalley and the Hutchins Consort, 2010. Accession 2010-011.
Access to Collection
Open for research. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
The Hutchins Collections consisting of 40.58 linear feet, spanning from the 1940s to 2009, documents Carleen Hutchins career through papers, research notes, clippings, photographs, correspondence, and media materials. Of particular importance are her notebooks where she recorded many of her acoustical experiments and the details on the construction of new instruments.
Arrangement note
The Hutchins Papers are arranged in 7 series: Series 1. Notebooks Series 2. General Files Series 3. Research and Writings Series 4. Other Authors’ Research and Writings Series 5. Photographic Materials Series 6. Media Series 7. Posters
Related archival Materials note
Related to the Musical Acoustics Research Library (MARL) Records, M1711.
- Series 1. Notebooks: Data on Existing Stringed Instruments and on the Construction of New Ones
  Scope and Contents
  Carleen Hutchins’ notebooks records work done on existing stringed instruments and, most importantly, the creation of new instruments.
  - Violin 260. Experiment: Dünnwald, Hutchins, and Rodgers, (bridge, soundpost, correspondence, figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, notes on tests, results, and adjustments), 1981-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Violins 260-262. Gleissner Wood. Rodgers, Mellem, Shaker Expt. NIU ’82, Toronto ’86 Bucur. “A Procedure for Objective Determination of Tone Quality of Violins,” Heinrich Dünnwald, (typescript, letters, figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, notes on tests, results, and adjustments), 1980-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Violins 263-268. Gleissner Wood. Rodgers, Mellem, Shaker Expt. NIU ’82, Toronto ’86 Bucur, (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, notes on tests, results, and adjustments), 1979-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Violins 269-271. Gleissner Wood. Rodgers, Mellem, Shaker Expt. NIU ’82, Toronto ’86 Bucur. “Physical Measurements on Sampling of European Spruce and Maple for Violin Top and Back Plates,” Morton A. Hutchins, (typescript, figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, notes on tests, results, and adjustments), 1979-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Violins 272-282, (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, notes on tests, results, and adjustments), 1979-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Violins 283-289, (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, notes on tests, results, and adjustments), 1979-1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Violins 290-297, (correspondence, figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, notes on tests, results, and adjustments), 1979-1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Violins 298-299, (correspondence, figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, notes on tests, results, and adjustments), 1979-1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Violins 440-450-Spruce Ages 1756-1981, (notes on wood types, ages of spruce, sealants and varnishes; correspondence; figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, and sound spectra) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Violins 47-484, Tuning Plates Harmonically to Each Other. Four Spots Test Top and Back, (sound spectra, free-plate-mode diagrams), 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Violin charts. Mode Tuning Eight Modes, (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, and notes), 1976-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Tests on Various Violins: Heinrich Dünnwald Response Curve Test; Plate Mode Frequencies, etc., (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, and notes), 1987-1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Methods of Changing the Frequency spacing (Delta) Between the A1 and B1 Modes of the Violin. Paper for the ASA Penn State, 1990 by Carleen M.Hutchins and Oliver E. Rodgers Part I, (annotated typescript, diagrams, charts, correspondence), 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Methods of Changing the Frequency spacing (Delta) Between the A1 and B1 Modes of the Violin. Paper for the ASA Penn State, 1990 by Carleen M. Hutchins and Oliver E. Rodgers Part II and Other Papers, (annotated typescript, diagrams, charts, correspondence), 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Some Effects of Prolonged Vibration on Violins, Carleen M. Hutchins and Herbert Ueltz Part I, (typescripts, figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, correspondence, and notes), 1980-1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Some Effects of Prolonged Vibration on Violins, Carleen M. Hutchins and Herbert Ueltz Part II, (reprints), 1980-1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mary Lee Esty, (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, and notes), 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Interpreting Spectral Data on Violins, by Joan E. Miller (reprint, diagrams, tables, spectra, notes), 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Joseph Conrad Construction of Violins and Violas (records of instrument type, wood, fittings, strings, tuning, start, sound spectra, and general comments), 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Carolyn Wison Fields: Tests and Adjustments on Violins and Violas, (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, correspondence, and notes), 1980-1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Andrea Castagneri Violas 15” / 8”: Results of Tests, (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, and notes), 1980-1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Violas 70-85: Tests and Adjustments, (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, and notes of sales and ownership of instruments), 1974-1998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Violas 86-98: Tests and Adjustments, (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, and notes of sales and ownership of instruments), 1972-1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Violas 211-224: Tests and Adjustments, (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, and notes of sales and ownership of instruments), 1975-1992 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Violas 225-233: Tests and Adjustments (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, results of effects of varnish, notes of sales and ownership of instruments), 1977-1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Violas 234-239: Tests on Gasparo and Elongated Strad Pattern Violas, (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, notes, and correspondence), 1979-1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Violas 240-259: Tests on Gasparo and Elongated Strad Pattern Violas, (figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, sound spectra, and notes), 1978-1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Violas 401-408. Free Plate Records and Humidity – Temp.; Experiments for Tuning Five Violas; Resonance Tests of the front and back plates, (tables, typescripts, sound spectra, diagrams, and notes), 1993-1995 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Violas 409-412. Resonance Tests of the front and back plates (tables, typescripts, sound spectra, diagrams, and notes), 1993-1995 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Violas 415-423. Resonance Tests of the front and back plates; varnish tests; notes of sales and ownership of instruments, (tables, typescripts, sound spectra, and diagrams), 1995-1998 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Violas 424-430, (sound spectra; figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes), 1986-1996 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Violas 431-434, (sound spectra,figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes), 1992-1996 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Viola Charts. Air – Wood, (graphs, notes), 1983-1995 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Wood and Viola Backs Comments: Acoustical Parameters for Violin and Viola Back Wood, Morton A. Hutchins, (typescripts, calculations, graphs), 1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Wood and Viola Backs Comments, (handwritten notes), 1984 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - A1-B1 Violas I: Hutchins-Kimball and Gasparo da Salo, (sound spectra and notes), 1976-1996 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - A1-B1 Violas II: Andrea Castagneri, Nicolas Audinot, Matteo Goffriller, (sound spectra and notes), 1984-1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Violas, Six Stradivarius Patterns, (tables, typescripts, sound spectra, and diagrams), 1959-1992 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Violas and Cellos Under Construction. Spot Mode Tuning. SGV – Back, (tables, diagrams, and notes), 1959-1997 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Hutchins’ Violin Octet: Treble Sopranos I, (sound spectra, photographs of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, and notes), 1971-1996 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Hutchins’ Violin Octet: Treble Sopranos II, (sound spectra, photographs of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, and notes), 1971-1996 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hutchins’ Violin Octet: Mezzos I, (sound spectra, photographs of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, and notes), 1968-1996 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Hutchins’ Violin Octet: Mezzos II, (sound spectra, photographs of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, and notes), 1968-1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Hutchins’ Violin Octet: Altos I, (sound spectra, photographs of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, and notes), 1974-1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Hutchins’ Violin Octet: Altos II, (sound spectra, photographs of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, and notes), 1974-1993 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Hutchins’ Violin Octet: Tenors, (sound spectra, photographs of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, and notes), 1971-1992 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Hutchins’ Violin Octet: Baritones I, (sound spectra, photographs of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, and notes), 1974-1996 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Hutchins’ Violin Octet: Baritones II, (sound spectra, photographs of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, and notes), 1974-1996 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Hutchins’ Violin Octet: Cellos I, (sound spectra, photographs of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, and notes), 1974-1996 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Hutchins’ Violin Octet: Cellos II, (sound spectra, photographs of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, and notes), 1974-1996 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - New Violin Family Image Archive. Index and Images, (lists, thumbnails), 2004 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Jesus Alonso Moral - Eigenmodes. Tests on the Hutchins Violin Octet I, 1980-1982 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Jesus Alonso Moral - Eigenmodes. Tests on the Hutchins Violin Octet II, 1980-1982 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Higher Air Modes in Violins, Violas and Cellos. Tests: Wood to Air, Air to Air, (tables); Varnish and Filler on Strip Tests with M. A. Hutchins, (tables); Free Plate Modes and Quality of Finished Instruments, (handwritten notes); Two letters CHM and Steve McCann, 1988; Sound spectra, misc., 1974-1988 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Viols: “Thoughts on Viols,” by David Strahle, (reprint); photographs of viol plates’ nodal area modes (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - A Measurable Effect of Long-Term Playing on Violin Family Instruments, ISMA Paris. Part I, (typescript, graphs, and notes), 1995 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - A Measurable Effect of Long-Term Playing on Violin Family Instruments, ISMA Paris. Part II, (typescript, graphs, and notes), 1995 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Bucur- Wood Data. Ten Spruce Tops. Different Ages, (notes, tables), 1756-1979 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Apgar. Apgar Quartet, (correspondence, slides, photographs, reprints, sound spectra, notes and eulogy), 1957-1996 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Stockholm Music Acoustics Conference. Tonal Effects of Interactions Between the Two Lowest Cavity Modes and Three Body Modes of the Violin (typescript, figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, graphs, slides), 1993 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Materials Research Society. Effects of Changes in Wood Stiffness Elements; Eigenmodes, (typescripts, correspondence, figures of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, graphs, slides, tables, reprint, and MRS Bulletin), 1994-1995 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Cutting Varnish Plates from Guitar Plates (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Project Platerik. Report of Measurements in St Andrews, by Ian Firth, (typescript, images of free plates and the nodal areas of modes, charts, and graphs), 1974-1976 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Research Briefs for the Violin Maker. Body Length Found to be the Primary Controlling Tone Quality Between Violins, Violas, Cellos, and Basses; Sympathetic Vibration and Coupling of Resonances,(reprint, photograph, typescripts, graphs of excitation frequency), 1987-1990 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - West Caldwell Calibration Laboratories Inc. Reports and Certificates of Calibration, (invoices, packing lists), 1994 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Photos I – Hutchins; Violin Octet; Ring Modes; Saunders Loudness Curve; John C. Schelleng; Sections of Wood; Eigenmodes; Jasha Heifetz (with autograph) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Photos II - Villaume’s Octobasse; Performance with the Violin Octet; Hutchins’ Workshop (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Slides, 35 mm I - Air Wood Tests; Stringed Instruments; Free Plates and the Nodal Areas of Modes, 1967-1970 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Slides, 35 mm II – Hutchins; Jansson; Stringed Instruments; Free Plates and the Nodal Areas of Modes; Graphs; Photo Sensor Tests, 1967-1973 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - The Catgut Acoustical Society Archives at the Samuel C. Williams Library, Stevens Institute of Technology, (list of holdings with handwritten notes probably by Joan Miller) (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Series 2. General Files: Correspondence, Clippings, Photos, Papers, Notes
  Carleen Hutchins’ General Files contain mainly her correspondence with instrument builders, acousticians, engineers, chemists, musical performers, in particular string players, and other business-related acquaintances.
  - A & M - Adolphus: A & M Wood Specialty Inc., 1986-05; Abelson, Elias, 2004; Abrasive Machine and Supply Co. 1959-89; Academic Press Inc., 1979-83; Acoustic Research, 1977; Academic Press, 1977-82; Acoustical Society of America, 2003-04; Addison, Barbara, 1973-2-73; Addison- Wesley Publishing Co., 1991-96; Adelaide University ,Australia, 1965; Adkisson, Huston D., 1973; Adolphus, Milton, 1987, 1959-2004 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Aebi - Alvord: Aebi, Willi, 1969-71; Akkoc, Can, 1986; Alaska Spruce Co. 1980-84; Alba, Ramon Alexander, 1981; Aldus Books Ltd., 1969-70; Allen, Brett, 1987-95; Allen, William B.,1992; Alpha Xi Delta, 1953-83; Aluminum violin, 1971; Alvord, Jean, 1977, 1953-1992 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1991-98; American Institute of Physics Part I, 1982-92, 1982-1998 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - American Institute of Physics, Part II, 1985-1992 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - American Machine & Tool Company, Inc. of Pennsylvania, 1982; American Philosophy Society, 1966-85, 1966-1985 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - American - Anton: American Scientist, 1981-92; American Scholar, 1994; Amos, Geo, 1964; Anadex Instruments, Inc. 1968; Anderson, Richard A., 1981; Anton, Sie, Part I, 1981-2000, 1964-2000 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Anton, Sie Part II, 1964-2000 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Apgar, Virginia, 1974-1976 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Armstrong - Aston: Armstrong, Theodore P., 1985-93; Artistic Productions Co. 1968; Arts Council of North-West Essex, 1982-84; Aston Magna Foundation for Music, 1976-93, 1968-1993 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Atwood - Ayers: Atwood, William B. 1996-98; Audio Engineering Society, 1997-2000; Axelrod, Herbert R. 1996; Ayers, Dean, 1977, 1977-2000 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Bachmann - Balser: Bachmann, J. H. Inc., 1990-92; Backhaus, H; Baer, Georgette, 1970-94; Bahr, Charles and Son, Inc. 1958-96; Bailey, Zuill, 1992; Balser, Dietrich, 1988-94, 1970-1996 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Balog - Basinger: Balog, Paul, 1982-91; Baltimore symphony, 1993; Bariska, M., 1976-97; Bartlett, Harriett, 1974-84; Basinger, Anne B. 1972, 1972-1997 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Basse - Benade: Basse Players, 1963-2004; Batchelder, Nancy, 1983-90; Beaver Engineering, 1977; Beldie, Ion Paul, 1997; Belgium Contest, 1962-63; Bell, James, F., 1991-93; Benade, Virginia, 1990, 1962-2004 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Benchmark - Bigelow: Benchmark Vol. 1 and 2. Charles Wiseman, 2004; Berger, Karl A. 1965; Benjamin, Phyllis, 1979; Baranek, Leo L. 1980-97; Berquist, Peter, 1977; Berman, William, 1970-99; Bethlehem Steel Co., 1963; Betts, Keter, 1980; Biasi, Paul (Basses), 1973; Bigelow, Arthur L., 1963, 1963-2004 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Bissinger, George, 1987-2003 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Bissolotti - Boeing: Bissolotti, Francesco, 1985-99; Blackburn, Thomas, 1979-86; Bloomfield Public Library, 1975-83; Blue Hill Kneisel Hall, 2005; Bobelock Case Co; Boeing Technology, 1983-88, 1975-1999 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Boggs - Boston: Boggs, L.R. 1994-95; Bonamini, Gabriele, 1989-91; Bondeson, Edith, 1962; Boonsliter, Paul C, 1969; Boothby, David, 1986; Boss, Greg; Boston Museum of Fine Arts, 1969-91; Boston Orchestra, 1964-67; Boston Post, 1949-97; Boston University, 1981-86, 1949-1997 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Boulez - Boyce: Boulez, Pierre, 1977; Bourgeois, Michel, 1980; Boutillon, Xavier, 1991-98; Bows; Boyden, J. H., 1968; Boyce, David H., 1968-1998 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Bram - Brown: Bram, Marjorie, 1965-1999; Brazil Television, 1998; British Broadcasting, 1996-98; Brown, Emily, 1977-79 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Brown - Bruel: Brown, Ann Marie, 1988; Brown, Thatcher M., 1980; Bruel & Kjaer Instruments, 1980-93, 1980-1993 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Bucknam- Butterfield: Bucknam, Ralph E., 1980-82; Burgess, David, 1986; Burgett, Harvey, 1990-93; Burkhard, M. D., 1965; Burner, Victor, 1995; Butterfield, Joespeh, 1995-99, 1965-1999 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - CBS - California: CBS News, 1980; CBS Technology Center 1971-78; California Academy of Sciences, 1962-74, 1962-1980 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Campbell - Carruth: Campbell, Patricia, 1998; Campbell, Edward and Mary, 1975-94; Campion, Deana, 1994; Canada Council, 1971; Canadian Broadcasting Corp. 1982; Canadian Television Network, LTD, 1968; Calnan Barbara, 1995-96; Cardiff University College, 1979; Cardwell, William T., 1984-94; Carlton Books, 1996; Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, 1989; Carruth, Alan, 1968-1998 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Cases for Musical Instruments, 1965-1997 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Castleman - Central: Castleman, Cahrles, 1974; Castronovo, John, 1966-89; Cello Congress 1982-97; Clarion State College, 1971; Chrisitan Science Monitor, 1966; Choral Arts Society, Alto Violins, 1981; Chemical and Engineering News, 1967; Celmer, Robert, 1987-89; Cellos, 1998; Cello Players, 1963-90; Cello Podium, 1989; Central Scientific Co. 1959, 1963-1998 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Chamuel - Chicago: Chamuel, Jacques, 1967; Chang, Gail Gordon, 1973-97; Chapman, Eric, 2003; Cheung, Judy, 2004; Chicago Museum of Science and Industry, 1994, 1967-2003 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Chicago - Christopher: Chicago Acoustical and Audio Group, 1967; Chin Rests; Chinmoy, Sri, 1997; Christopher Columbus Fellowship, 1997, 1967-1997 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Chrysalis - Cole: Chrysalis Foundation, 1989; Cincinnati Enquirer, 1974; Cincinnati University, 1967; Claremont quartet, 1955; Clark, Jean; Clark, Melville, 1993; Clarke, Nancy, 1975-99; Cleary, John F. 1966; Cleveland Orchestra, 1968-69; Cleveland Quartet, 1988-95; Cole, Anne, 1998; Cole, Orlando, 1980-82, 1955-1999 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Coletta - Conversions: Coletta, Harold, 1973-90; Colwell Crating, Inc. 1994; Concordia University, 1992; Connoly, Justin, 1966; Albert Constantine & Co., 1975-79; Coppedge, W.K. 1969-70; Continuo, 1992-97; Conversions, 1973-1994 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Conyers - Cornell: Conyers, A. R. 1972-73; Cook, R. O. 1979-83; Core Hoeard & Co. Inc., 1982; Cornell, Alumni News, 1965-92, 1965-1983 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Cornell - Craighill: Cornell Women’s Club of N. J., 1967-82; Cote, Wilfred, 1985-98; Crates, 1994; Craighill, Lloyd R., 1982-99, 1967-1999 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - CRC - Cremona: CRC Press, Inc., 1988-89; Creitz, Lowell, (tenor); Crystal-Sporer, Kacy, 1979-95; Cremona, School of Violin Making, 1969-99; Cremona, Bruce Carlson, 1983-84, 1969-1999 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Cremona Italian Publications, 1983-86 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Cremona Misc., 1969-83 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Croen - Czechoslovakia: Croen, Thomas Oliver, 1998; Cunningham, Nicholas, 1977-99; Customs, US and Foreign., 1973-87; Czechoslovakia, 1979-93, 1973-1999 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - D’Addario - Dobbins: D’Addario, 1997; Daily News NYC, 1966; Dalton, David, 1991; Dateline in Science, 1966; Decker, John, 1991; Delaware State Music Teachers, 1962-66; Dello-Stritto, John, 1981; Delmhorst Instrument Co., 1977; Denver University, 1976; DeVilbiss, Alan J., 1983; Dickens Frank, 1977; Dickstein, Bernard, 1962-76; Dienel, Hans, 1970-76; Dillingham, Frank, 1987; D’Janni, John, 1975-76; Dobbins, Peter, 2004, 1962-2004 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Dover Publications, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Dow - Early: Dow Chemical Co. 1972; Dunham, James, 1977; Dünnwald, Heinrich, 1981-1999; Dunworkin Club of Montclair; Durham University, 1975; Dwyer, Doriot Anthony, 1989-90; Early Instruments and Music, 1976-87, 1972-1999 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Eagan - Essex: Eagan, Thomas M. & Son Inc., 1960-61; Edge, Norman F., 1992; Eiser, H. Inc., 1964; Electronic Music, 1965; Electronic Violins, 1939; Elema-Schönander AB, Stockholm Sweden; Ellison, Warren, 2003; Encyclopedic Dictionary of Violin and Bow Makers, 1959-61; Engelbrecht, Paul, 2004; Erskine, Margaret; Essex, Lady Christine, 1980, 1939-2004 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Etymotic Research, 1987-1999 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Evans – Fischler: Evans, Barbara; Evans, Betty, 1999; Evans, Peter, 1974-98; Evans, Ruth Esther, 1968-77; Evans, Sidney LTD. Violin Supplies, 1977; Finch, Thomas L.; Falk, Nina, 1988-93; Felde, Maurice, 1967; Feeney, John, 1980; Feldman, Ronald, 1979; Fermilab, Christopher, Field, 1991-98; Fielding, Frank, 1994-97; Fischler, Franz, 1984-86, 1968-1999 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Fitzgerald - Forsyth: Fitzgerald, Edwin R., 1991-1998; Flagg, Thomas J., 1970; Flanagan, Dennis, 1988-2003; Fletcher, Harvey, 1967; Fletcher, Neville H., 1980; Fontenot, Royne, 1985-1987; Force Machinery Co., 1968; Ford Foundation, 1974; Forsking och Framstegg, 1982; Forsyth, Michael, 1988 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Foster – Frank: Foster, Colin, 1982-1983; Foster, Daniel, 1983-1987; Foundation Center, N. Y., 1973-1977; Fox, Joyce, 1982; Fox Technology Corp., 1982; Foy, George, 1977-1993; Frank, Helmut, 1991-1992 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - French - Fryden: French, Mark, 1994-1998; Frenkel, Thomas A., 1973; Frets, 1981; Freidlen, Benjamin, 1993; Friedlander, F.G., 1952; Frostburg State College, 1971; Four Seasons Conso rt, 1962; Fry, William S., 1982-1988; Fryden, Lars (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Gard –Gibran: Gard Stephen, 1966; Garden State Arts Center, 1991; General Electric, 1982; General Radio, 1959-81; Giddings, Lorrain, 1983; Gietzem, Alfred, 1966; Gibran, Kahlil, 1993-94, 1959-1993 (Box 25, Folder 1)